Hello everyone, how are you all? I am
Amit Raj Sharma, your personal advisor, and you are
watching Yudh Real. Today's video is
hosted by Mr. Shyam Yadav.
Mr. Yadav,
thank you very much for your comment. Because of your comment,
we will understand the life savings plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited.
Mr. Yadav commented
in the comments section of the Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited Savings Plan video. If you
want to understand the details of a short savings plan,
check the life insurance playlist.
You will find the video, or
you will also find a link to it in today's video on the end screen.
Watch the video. Now I want to remind you of one thing.
Every
video on the channel is continuously being released according to your suggestions, questions, and comments.
If you want
us to continue to release videos like this for you,
please like the video,
subscribe to the channel, and turn on all notifications.
If you are watching this video
on the Facebook page right now, please
like and follow the page so
that you can stay connected with us. Do
n't forget to share the video.
Tell us in the comment section on which topic you want the next video to be.
Now we will directly know the details.
This life savings plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited is
not subject to market risk rules.
In simple words, it
is not connected to the market and the performance of the company will
also not have any effect on it
because this plan itself is non-participating.
In simple words, this is a
life insurance policy giving you guaranteed returns.
We will understand how all the benefits will be available by way of example.
Now let us know the eligibility criteria. The
entry limit is from one
year to 55 years. The maturity
limit is from 18 years to
65 years.
You get more than one option for premium payment term. The
first is single premium. The second is limited pay. The
third is regular pay. If you take the single pay
option, then you will be able to pay
premium for 10 years or 15 years at one time.
Now when it comes to the policy term,
see, the policy term limit is according to the number of options for different premium
payment terms.
Single pay or  Six Way
Six Way means paying premium pack for 6 years continuously,
so in such a situation, the option
of positive term up to 10 years, 15 years or 20 years
is available, we can choose any one option from 9 years or 12 years to
pay the premium continuously, so the
option of positive term of 15 or 20 years can be available,
in regular pay, the
premium will have to be paid continuously for the same number of years as the policy term, that is,
10 years and 15 years, okay,
now we will know here
what is the minimum premium limit, if
you take the single premium option, then you will have to pay at
least Rs 20000, you will
not be able to pay more than the maximum premium in this plan, with
regular limited pay, the minimum sum assured will be
₹5000 annually and the maximum sum assured will be ₹1 lakh, the
minimum sum assured will be ₹25000, if the
limited sum assured is taken on regular pay, then the
minimum sum assured will be ₹50000, the maximum sum assured
limit in the plan will be 10
You cannot get more than one lakh rupees. Talking about the mode of
premium, if you
take the annual, half-yearly, slow and main to monthly option, then
auto debit will be done from your account only. Rest, there is
single premium, that is also a mode of
premium. The waiting period in it is 90 days.
I will tell you how it will be reduced by the end of the video with an example. For
now, let's move towards the benefit.
First of all, there is death benefit in it.
Normal death is also covered and
accidental death is also covered.
In case of normal death, you will get death and record guarantee
addition. If your nominee
dies due to an accident, then the normal death
benefit plus whatever is there will be, you will
get it again, which means the amount will be doubled.
In case of accidental death, if
you have taken the policy for a minor, then keep the age of the family till
18 years. The
maturity benefit is that you will get
your guaranteed addition accumulated along with the maturity sum shot in it,
which we are calling matured guarantee addition,
meaning accumulation will be given to you.  You will
get samosas on maturity. Order on
maturity or somewhere on maturity on summer
short. This is the total premium that you pay
basic during the premium payment
term. The same amount will be your
maturity on chamber short. If you have
taken the limited pay option to pay the premium, then the
premium payment will start
after completion. The guaranteed addition and
addition will start, meaning the guaranteed
addition will start accumulating. If you have
given the option of regular pay premium, then when the 8 years are
completed, then
you will start getting the guaranteed addition. If
you have taken the single pay option to pay the premium, then
after the first year you will
start getting the guaranteed addition.
How will you get it? Let's take an example,
here, let's take a man,
his age is 35 years. He is taking a 20-year term
and the premium
payment term is 12 years.
Annually, he pays only ₹10,000. If you
want to know
how much amount can be received in this, then first of all we will
talk if you are taking a ₹10,000 running pack.
So how much will the sum assured be 10
times? If we multiply 10000 by 10, then it
means that they will get a cover of ₹1 lakh here. That
means the basic understanding will be
what is the premium payment term option
here, limited because it is a 12 year
option, so in such a situation, when will the guaranteed addition start
accumulating, after the
premium payment is complete, so
now what we need to
know here is on what basis is the guaranteed addition calculated, the
guaranteed addition rate is applied on maturity on sum assured,
I am telling you this in a simple way,
otherwise if you go technical then you
may get confused, maturity on sum assured
means you know the
sum of all the total premiums paid, so
how much is our total amount here, 20000
because the premium payment for 12 years is the basic
premium of ₹10000. Now if we
calculate the period of guaranteed addition, then we will
subtract the premium payment term from the policy term,
so 8  The guaranteed addition period of one year will be calculated here. The
guaranteed addition rate
given here is 10.5 percent. It will be better to
think about it because whenever you do it,
you will have the policy bond, then
this will be written on it. Now what is the total sum of guaranteed
addition? If we calculate 10.6% of ₹120000 and
multiply it by eight, then
we get 120, which is 10.5 percent
and multiply it by eight, then the
amount is 1376.
What happened to the maturity benefit? If we add 120000 and 1 lakh 1
thousand 376, then
they will get an amount of 2 lakh 21376. It means that the
premium that is being sold has almost doubled, it has
more than doubled, I mean it has almost
doubled, right, so you are getting
guaranteed benefit, this is what the
company says according to their policy document.
Now we will understand the death benefit, so
we will understand it here.  Let us assume that the death has occurred,
10 years of the policy have been completed,
premiums have been paid, if it has happened then
what is the benefit,
guarantee addition, so first of all we will understand what is the
sum assured on death here, we are assuming here
that it is a normal death, so this is
not an accidental death, so understand and
what is death, your basic seed or whatever
premium you have paid till the date of death
without other taxes, 105% of that basic seed dot
ours is ₹1 lakh in this plan, right and suppose you have paid
premium for 11 years, the
premium was ₹10000, so if we multiply it by 11 then the
amount becomes 110000, right if we take out
105% of it, then an
amount of 12500 will be settled here, the death
benefit says sum assured on death and an
addition, now because
death will happen before the premium payment term, then the sum
assured guarantee addition amount here will become zero, so
in such a situation the death benefit will be
115500 will be given to their nominee,
if there is an accidental death of the wife, then the
same amount will be added to it.
Talking about the grace period, there is a
grace period of 15 days with the monthly mode of
premium, that is, if you
pay monthly premium, if you pay half-yearly or yearly slow
premium, then
you get a grace period of 30 days. There is a free loan
period of 15 days in it. If you have taken the
policy directly from the company, through an
indirect source or online yourself, then
you get a free loan period of 30 days in it.
Now let's talk about the waiting
period, it is 90 days. If there is a
death within the first 90 days, then in such a case, the
nominee gets back the premium paid, that is,
death is not covered within the first 90 days.